# Santiago Hidalgo Ocampo

Address: Calle 112 N 76D - 09, Medellín, Colombia +57 3125008717  $\begin{array}{c} {\bf Email:\ santihidalgo 311309@gmail.com} \\ {\bf github.com/sanhidalgo o} \end{array}$ 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/santiago-hidalgo-ocampo-199324160/

## **EDUCATION**

• EAFIT University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, GPA: 4.60/5.0

• I.E Diego Echavarría Misas

High School, specializing in information systems programming. , GPA: 4.7/5.0

Medellín, Colombia

Intended Grad: Jul. 2023
Medellín, Colombia

Jan. 2017 - Nov. 2018

# **SUMMARY**

Nowadays, I am a senior computer science student and a cloud administrator. I have been passionate about software development since high school. I enjoy solving problems using computers to improve and simplify processes. I have solid experience with Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS) administration environments, experience with network administration (LDAP, DNS, load balancing, VPC, etc), and experience with containers (Docker) and container orchestration (Amazon ECS and Kubernetes). In addition, I have proficiency in scripting languages such as Bash, Powershell, node and python. I have worked on server automation with Terraform, Serverless Framework, Ansible, Vagrant, and other configuration management tools. Also, I have the ability to effectively establish and maintain working relationships across disciplines across the organization. Great sense of commitment and responsibility orientation. All tasks are done and achieved with a high degree of discipline

and a goal-oriented manner. Besides that, I stand out for my good attitude to learn and share my acquired knowledge. I care about growing together with my work team and being able to solve the problems that arise on the road.

# **EXPERIENCE**

• PYXIS S.A.S

Cloud administrator

Medellín, Colombia
Sept. 2021 - Present

I worked in cloud management on AWS:

\* Design and implementation of multi-account environments through AWS Control Tower.

- \* Design and implementation of architectures for notifications using different AWS services such as: SES, Lambda, S3, API Gateway, SQS, Step Functions and ECS.
- \* Use of scripting languages [Node, Bash, Python].
- \* Use Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tools like Terraform and Serverless Framework to deploy infrastructure on AWS
- \* Use Configuration as Code (CaC) tools like Ansible to deploy and configure web services on AWS.
- \* Use ECS to manage container orchestration applying best practices for application high availability. (ALB, Auto Scaling, etc.)

## Accelogic, LLC » Software Acceleration Specialists

Medellín, Colombia March 2021 - June 2021

I worked in cluster management for HPC on AWS:

- \* Cluster management for HPC on AWS through ParallelCluster service.
- \* Use of Vagrant as virtualizing automation tool.
- \* Use of Ansible as a provisioning automation tool.
- \* Install and compile HPC applications on AWS clusters

#### • EAFIT University

Research Assistant

Systems Administrator at Apolo Supercomputing Center

Medellín, Colombia

September. 2019 - May 2021

Apolo Supercomputing Center is EAFIT's cluster. I worked as administrator of Linux systems. Fields where I have developed:

- \* Use of scripting languages [Python, Bash].
- \* Use of Vagrant as virtualizing automation tool.
- \* Use of Virtualbox and kvm as virtualizer tools.
- \* Use of Git and Subversion for version management.
- \* Operating systems architecture.
- \* Use of Ansible as a provisioning automation tool.
- \* Install and compile HPC applications for cluster users.
- \* Install, configure and manage an identity management system like FreeIPA.

#### PROJECTS AND EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

• ApoloQ (December. 2020): Development of a slurm simulator (resource manager system) integrated with a dashboard in order to display relevant information of the execution of algorithms on a supercomputer. [PHP, Laravel, MySQL]

• Inmobile (June 2020): Development of a mobile application connected to an Arduino that allowed to control hardware resources. Project focused on domotics. [Java, Arduino, C++, App Inventor]

## AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Best High School student of Institución Educativa Diego Echavarría Misas (2018).
- Selected for an undergraduate scholarship valued at 120 million COP (around 30.000 USD), based on excellence in official High School Graduation Exam. Generación E Scholarship 2019.
- 1st place out of 200 at GigaCampus 2018. Municipal High School Software Development Competition.
- International internship in Santiago de Chile. Technological Mission 2018.
- 3<sup>rd</sup> place out of 450 in the municipal programming marathon. Competition of high school students of Medellin city.
- 3<sup>rd</sup> place out of 300 ASC20-21 Student Supercomputing Challenge (Virtual).

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Languages: Python (1.5 years), Java (2 years), Bash (1.5 years), node (6 months).
- Technologies: Linux (3 years), Git (3 years), Subversion (2 years), Ansible (1.5 years), Vagrant(1 year), AWS (1 year), Terraform (6 months), Serverless Framework (6 months).

## Courses

- Web Applications for Everybody Specialization Coursera
- Fundamentals of Parallelism on Intel Architecture Coursera
- Desarrollador C# Netec, Santiago de Chile

#### LANGUAGES

- English (B2 Level)
- Spanish (Native)